Norman mss. III, 1958-1983 LMC 2668
Lilly Library
Norman mss. III
1958-1983
2007
Lilly Library
Norman, Frank
LMC 2668
16 Boxes
4 folios oversize
The Norman mss. III, ca. 1958–1983, consist of scripts, music scores, manuscript fragments, proofs, publications, photographs, and programs of plays of the work of Frank Norman, including materials relating to Fings Ain't Wot The Used T'be, Bang to Rights, and Dodgem Greaser.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 2007
Biographical Note
Frank Norman, 1930-1980, was a British playwright and novelist. An illegitimate son, he was born in Bristol and grew up in children's homes in London, including Dr. Barnardo's children's home from age 7 to 15. He spent time in prison for petty thefts, including a 3-year sentence at Camp Hill Prison. After his release in 1956, he began driving a van while working on a prison memoir, Bang to Rights. This memoir was serialized in the magazine Encounter by Encounter editor Stephen Spender and was published as a standalone work with a foreword by Raymond Chandler in 1958. The book preserved Norman's spelling and grammar; Norman's education in the orphanages had been spotty, and he claimed to have been illiterate at age 14.
After the success of Bang to Rights, Norman began working on a play Fings Ain't Wot They Used T'Be (1960), which was developed into a musical and produced by Joan Littlewood's Theatre Workshop and then transferred to the West End.
In addition to Bangs to Rights and Fings Ain't Wot They Used T'Be, Norman wrote novels; non-fiction; stage plays; a memoir of his time at Barnardo's, Banana Boy (1969); and an autobiography, Why Fings Went West (1975).
Scope and Contents
The Norman mss. III, ca. 1958–1983, consist of scripts, music scores, manuscript fragments, proofs, publications, photographs, and programs of plays of the work of Frank Norman, including materials relating to Fings Ain't Wot The Used T'be, Bang to Rights, and Dodgem Greaser.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by topic (Writing, Press, Correspondence, Photographs, Audio, and Miscellaneous), then chronologically to the best of this author's ability. Original order was not discernable when surveying the collection originally and materials were scattered across 13 boxes. The articles series deviates from topic-chronology order due to the bulk of drafts being undated. This sub-series is arranged by alphabetical order of titles of the articles. Boxes 16 and 17 are materials acquired at a later date and were kept in their original order but represented within the corresponding sub-series in the inventory. Several items are out for conservation at the time of this note including posters, photographs, and newspaper clipping scrapbooks. Several of these and two other items are oversized and noted as such accordingly. While most photographs are together in Box 14, four folders of photographs are kept in box 4 because they were curated for a book Frank did not get to finish writing before his passing in 1980.
Related Material
See Norman mss. and Norman mss. II, also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Theater; Theater --Great Britain.; Authors, English; Prisoners' writings; Norman, Frank; Littlewood, Joan
- Writing, 1958-2000 (Box 1)
  - Books, 1964-2000
    - Bang to Rights (Box 1)
      - Bang to Rights Proof (Box 1)
    - Stand on Me (Box 1)
      - Manuscript (Box 1)
    - Soho Night and Day (Box 1)
      - Manuscript Fragments 1/2 (Box 1)
      - Manuscript Fragments 2/2 (Box 1)
      - Notes
    - The Monkey Pulled His Hair, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
      - Typedraft with corrections 1/2, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
      - Typedraft with corrections 2/2, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    - Barney Snip (Box 1)
      - Typedraft with corrections 1/3 (Box 1)
      - Typedraft with corrections 2/3 (Box 1)
      - Typedraft with corrections 3/3 (Box 1)
      - Typedraft Fragment with Corrections (Box 1)
    - Banana Boy (Box 1)
      - Banana Boy Notes (Box 1)
      - Foreward (Box 1)
    - Norman's London (Box 1)
      - Early Article Draft Reprints (Box 1)
    - Lock'em Up and Count'em (Box 1)
      - Printer's Proof with Corrections, 1970 (Box 1)
      - Interviews and Foreward (Box 1)
      - Interviews A (Box 1)
      - Interviews B (Box 1)
      - Interviews and Conclusion (Box 1)
    - Dodgem Greaser (Box 1)
      - Printer's Proof June 14, 1971 (Box 1)
      - Printer's Proof with Dust Jacket June 14, 1971 (Box 1)
      - Typedraft with corrections 1/2 (Box 1)
      - Typedraft with corrections 2/2 (Box 1)
      - "Printer's Copy" December 1971 1/2 (Box 2)
      - "Printer's Copy" December 1971 2/2 (Box 2)
      - Typedraft Fragment with Corrections (Box 2)
      - Synopsis (Box 16)
    - The Lives of Frank Norman, 1971 (Box 2)
      - Printer's Proof with Corrections 9/29/1971 (Box 2)
      - Printer's Proof with Corrections 11/30/1971 (Box 2)
      - Notes (Box 2)
    - One of Our Own (Box 2)
      - "One of Our Own Inserts" (Box 2)
      - Printer's Proof with corrections c.1973 (Box 2)
      - "Blitz Kid Chapter 1" (Box 2)
      - Chapter 1 Draft (Box 2)
      - "Cockney Dynasty Carbon Copy" 1/2 (Box 2)
      - "Cockney Dynasty Carbon Copy" 2/2
      - Printer's Copy with Corrections 1/3 (Box 2)
      - Printer's Copy with Corrections 2/3 (Box 2)
      - Printer's Copy with Corrections 3/3 (Box 2)
      - Partial Typedraft (Box 2)
      - Synopsis A (Box 2)
      - "Blitz Kid" Synopsis (Box 16)
      - Synopsis B (Box 16)
      - James Hale Editing (Box 16)
    - Much Ado About Nuffink (Box 2)
      - Printer's Proof (Box 2)
      - Incomplete Printer's Proof (Box 3)
      - Drafts with Editing (Box 3)
      - Typedraft A with corrections 1/3 (Box 3)
      - Typedraft A with corrections 2/3 (Box 3)
      - Typedraft A with corrections 3/3 (Box 3)
      - Typedraft B with Corrections 1/3 (Box 3)
      - Typedraft B with Corrections 2/3 (Box 3)
      - Typedraft B with Corrections 3/3 (Box 3)
      - Synopsis (Box 3)
      - Chapter 1 Typedraft
      - Plot Outline (Box 3)
      - James Hale Editing Draft, 1973 (Box 16)
      - Richard Simon Editing Draft (Box 16)
    - Why Fings Went West (Box 3)
      - Typedraft with Corrections (Box 3)
      - Picture Selections (Box 3)
      - Printer's Proof "For Sharon's Edification" (Box 3)
      - Typedraft Fragment with Corrections (Box 3)
    - Down and Out in High Society, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
      - Hodder and Stoughton Typedraft with Corrections 1/2 1976 (Box 3)
      - Hodder and Stoughton Typedraft with Corrections 2/2 1976 (Box 3)
      - Printer's Proof with Corrections September 1975 (Box 3)
      - Chapter 5 Typedraft (Box 3)
    - The Fake's Progress (Box 3)
      - Printer's Proof 1977 (Box 3)
      - "The Continuing Tom Keating Drama" (Box 3)
      - Foreward Typedraft (Box 3)
      - Tom Keating Notes Orange Notebook (Box 16)
      - Tom Keating Notes Red Notebook (Box 16)
    - Too Many Crooks Spoil the Caper (Box 3)
      - Editing Notes (Box 3)
      - Printer's Proof, Bound with Corrections
      - Proof Facsimile with Corrections (Box 4)
      - "Manuscript Bits of Too Many Crooks" (Box 4)
      - "Draft Bits" with Corrections and Notes (Box 4)
      - Typedraft A - Uncorrected (Box 4)
      - Typedraft B - Corrections and Retype Notes (Box 4)
      - Typedraft C with Corrections 1/2 (Box 4)
      - Typedraft C with Corrections 2/2 (Box 4)
      - Typedraft - Chapters 2, 3, 19 (Box 4)
      - Front Flap Draft (Box 4)
      - Typedraft D w/ Corrections 1/2 (Box 4)
      - Typedraft D w/ Corrections 2/2 (Box 4)
    - The Dead Butler Caper, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
      - Plot Synopsis
      - Mrs. S. Fleming Typedraft 1/2 1977 (Box 4)
      - Mrs. S. Fleming Typedraft 2/2 1977 (Box 4)
      - "Bits of Editing" (Box 4)
      - "Plot as Worked Out in Venice" (Box 4)
      - "Early Draft Bits" 1/3 (Box 4)
      - "Early Draft Bits" 2/3 (Box 4)
      - "Early Draft Bits" 3/3 (Box 4)
      - "Unused Bits" (Box 5)
      - Manuscript A 1/2 (Box 5)
      - Manuscript A 2/2 (Box 5)
      - Typedraft Fragments with Corrections (Box 5)
      - Printer's Proof Facsimile 1978 (Box 5)
      - "Blue Blood" Typedraft 1/2 (Box 5)
      - "Blue Blood" Typedraft 2/2 (Box 5)
      - "Whodunnit" Typedraft 1/2 (Box 5)
      - "Whodunnit" Typedraft 2/2 (Box 5)
    - The Baskerville Caper (Box 5)
      - "Preliminary Copy" 1/3 (Box 5)
      - "Preliminary Copy" 2/3 (Box 5)
      - "Preliminary Copy" 3/3 (Box 5)
      - Chapter 3 Manuscript (Box 5)
      - Research and Typedraft Fragments 1/2 (Box 5)
      - Research and Typedraft Fragments 1/2 (Box 5)
      - Baskerville Dedication and Chapter 1 (Box 5)
      - Gillon Aitkin Copy with Corrections 1/3 (Box 5)
      - Gillon Aitkin Copy with Corrections 2/3 (Box 5)
      - Gillon Aitkin Copy with Corrections 3/3 (Box 5)
      - Star Books Copy with Corrections 1/3 (Box 6)
      - Star Books Copy with Corrections 2/3 (Box 6)
      - Star Books Copy with Corrections 3/3 (Box 6)
      - "Early Draft" with Corrections 1/2 (Box 6)
      - "Early Draft" with Corrections 2/2 (Box 6)
    - Unpublished Works (Box 6)
      - The Breast Stroke (Box 6)
        - Synopsis A (Box 6)
        - Synopsis B (Box 16)
      - Apparently the Heir (Box 6)
        - Plot Notes (Box 6)
        - Synopsis (Box 6)
        - Synopsis and Story Line (Box 6)
        - Richard Scott Simon Correspondence 1975 (Box 6)
        - Story Line (Box 6)
      - Sex in Britain Since World War II (Box 6)
        - Research Planning (Box 6)
        - Richard Scott Simon LTD Synopsis (Box 6)
        - Synopsis (Box 16)
      - Untitled Richard Watts Memoir (Box 6)
        - Tape Transcription (Box 6)
        - Correspondence 1976 (Box 6)
        - Richard Watts Jr. Interview Notes 1975 (Box 6)
      - The Last Banana Skin (Box 6)
        - "Drafts and Last Articles" (Box 6)
        - Introduction Facsimile (Box 6)
        - Hodgkin's Research Notes (Box 6)
        - Typedraft Fragments (Box 6)
        - Bernard Kops Correspondence 2000 (Box 6)
        - Photograph Correspondence (Box 6)
      - Broadway Caper (Box 6)
        - Draft (Box 6)
      - The Gilded Gutter (Box 7)
        - Synopsis (Box 7)
      - Product of the War (Box 7)
        - Synopsis (Box 7)
      - Unidentified Drafts (Box 7)
        - Watch Theft typedraft (Box 7)
        - Hospital Typedraft (Box 7)
        - Miriam Hope (Box 7)
      - Francis Bacon Biography (Box 16)
        - Typedraft (Box 16)
  - Scripts (Box 7)
    - Stage (Box 7)
      - Fings Ain't Wot They Used T'Be, 1958-1960 (Box 7)
        - Music Scores (Box 7)
        - Richard Scott Simon Music Score Facsimiles (Box 7)
        - Helga Greene Script Copy (Box 7)
        - "Master Copy" Script 1960 (Box 7)
        - Frank Norman Personal Script Copy (Box 7)
        - Greenwich Theatre Script 1958 (Box 7)
        - "Helga's Files" Script Copy 1/3 (Box 7)
        - "Helga's Files" Script Copy 2/3 (Box 7)
        - "Helga's Files" Script Copy 3/3 (Box 7)
        - The Tramshed Flyer (Box 7)
        - Fings Ain't Wot They Used T'Be (Down Under) (Box 16)
        - Polish Fings Draft (Box 16)
      - A Kayf Up West (Box 7)
        - Cast List (Box 7)
        - "Theatre Workshop '64" Script (Box 7)
        - Typedraft with Corrections (Box 7)
        - Script Yellow Binding (Box 7)
        - Script Cobalt Binding (Box 7)
        - Script Deep Green Binding (Box 7)
        - Music Scores (Box 7)
      - The Sufferings of Peter Obnizov (Box 7)
        - Rehearsal Script (Box 7)
        - Susan Hanson Sript Copy (Box 7)
        - Early Story Draft (Box 16)
      - Insideout, 1967-1968 (Box 7)
        - Cast List and Audition Schedule (Box 7)
        - Script Typedraft with Notes 11/17/1968 - A (Box 7)
        - Script Typedraft with Notes 11/17/1968 - B (Box 7)
        - Script 1967 (Box 7)
        - Script Brown Binding 1968 (Box 7)
        - Script Navy Binding 1968 (Box 7)
        - Script Brown Binding 1968 (Box 7)
        - Nigel Hawthorne Script 1968 (Box 7)
        - Typedraft Fragments (Box 7)
      - Costa Packet (Box 8)
        - Incomplete Script Facsimile (Box 8)
        - Draft and Notes 1/2 (Box 16)
        - Draft and Notes 2/2 (Box 16)
      - Rough Trade (Box 8)
        - Act One Scene One Typedraft (Box 8)
        - "First Draft" 1972 (Box 8)
        - Typedraft A (Box 8)
        - Typedraft B (Box 8)
        - Loose Papers (Box 16)
      - Wot a Caper (Box 8)
        - Script Red Binding A (Box 8)
        - Damerel Caper Draft (Box 8)
        - Script Blue Binding (Box 8)
        - Script Red Binding B (Box 8)
        - Script Red Binding C (Box 8)
        - Typedraft with Notes (Box 8)
        - Gaylord Caper Draft (Box 8)
        - Gaylord Caper Draft with Suggestions (Box 8)
        - Typedraft with Corrections (Box 8)
        - Typedraft Fragment (Box 8)
      - Backstage (Box 8)
        - Typedraft with Corrections A (Box 8)
        - Typedraft with Corrections B (Box 8)
        - Synopsis (Box 8)
        - Act One Scene One Typedraft (Box 8)
      - Provenance (Box 8)
        - Act One Scene One Fragment (Box 8)
    - TV (Box 8)
      - Londoner's (Box 8)
        - Just Call Me Lucky (Box 8)
          - Just Call Me Lucky First Draft (Box 8)
          - Camera Screenplay Facsimile (Box 8)
      - Crown Court (Box 8)
        - Incorrigible Rogue (Box 8)
          - Screenplay Facsimile, 1976 (Box 8)
          - Planning Notes (Box 8)
          - Episode 1 Typedraft Fragments (Box 8)
          - Episode 1 Screenplay (Box 8)
          - Episode 2 Typedraft Fragments (Box 8)
          - Episode 2 Screenplay Facsimile (Box 8)
          - Episode 2 Screenplay (Box 8)
          - Episode 3 Typedraft Fragments (Box 8)
          - Episode 3 Screenplay Facsimile (Box 8)
          - Episode 3 Screenplay Facsimile (Box 8)
        - Synopsis (Box 16)
      - Banana Boy TV Adaptation (Box 8)
        - Screenplay A September 1977 1/2 (Box 8)
        - Screenplay A September 1977 2/2 (Box 8)
        - Screenplay B with Corrections September 1977 (Box 8)
        - 175 Page Screenplay (Box 8)
        - Screenplay 1/2 (Box 8)
        - Screenplay 2/2 (Box 8)
        - Pitch Screenplay Part One 1/2 (Box 9)
        - Pitch Screenplay Part One 2/2 (Box 9)
        - Pitch Screenplay Part Two 1/3 (Box 9)
        - Pitch Screenplay Part Two 2/3 (Box 9)
        - Pitch Screenplay Part Two 3/3 (Box 9)
      - Princetown (Box 9)
        - "Princetown Historical Background" (Box 9)
        - Typedraft Fragment (Box 9)
        - TV Pitch (Box 9)
        - "Format for Television Series" (Box 9)
        - Pitch Bible (Box 9)
      - Minder (Box 9)
        - Occupational Hazard (Box 9)
          - Screenplay Draft with Corrections (Box 9)
          - Episode Summary with Corrections (Box 9)
          - Screenplay (Box 9)
        - The Home Secretary's Gold Watch (Box 9)
          - Synopsis (Box 9)
          - Synopsis Facsimile (Box 9)
      - Tallentine (Box 9)
        - TV Pitch (Box 9)
      - One of Our Own (Box 9)
        - Typedraft Fragments (Box 9)
        - TV Synopsis A (Box 9)
        - TV Synopsis B (Box 16)
      - Power Base (Box 9)
        - TV Pitch (Box 9)
      - Scarface (Box 9)
        - Screenplay Draft (Box 9)
    - Movie (Box 9)
      - In the Nick (Box 9)
        - "First Draft" (Box 9)
        - "Wot Goes Up" Draft 1960 (Box 9)
      - Fings Ain't Wot They Used T'Be (Box 9)
        - Screenplay (Box 9)
      - Lords of the Manor (Box 9)
        - Screenplay (Box 9)
      - Collisions (Box 9)
        - Screenplay Fragments (Box 9)
      - TV Commercials (Box 16)
        - Sheila and Eggs Draft (Box 16)
  - Articles (Box 9)
    - Drafts (Box 9)
    - African Diary (Box 16)
      - Barnardo (Box 9)
      - Book Reviews A (Box 9)
      - Book Reviews B (Box 16)
      - Book Plugging (Box 16)
      - Bridge of the Victoria Falls (Box 16)
      - Clive Barnes (Box 9)
      - Cockney Dialect Article (Box 16)
      - Colin MacInnes (Box 9)
      - Dial a Hooker (Box 9)
      - A Drink at Mentmore (Box 9)
      - "A Few Drinks at Mentmore" (Box 16)
      - Farewell to Hampstead (Box 9)
      - Festival of Britain (Box 9)
      - The French Pub - Soho (Box 16)
      - A Geezer Called Sammie (Box 16)
      - Getting Laid in Manhatten (Box 9)
      - Getting Out of the Nick (Box 9)
      - Henry Fonda A (Box 9)
      - Henry Fonda B (Box 16)
      - Interview Transcript Club International Article (Box 9)
      - Insideout (Box 9)
      - The Job (Box 9)
      - Lack of Sex (Box 16)
      - Limey at Large (Box 9)
      - Love Story (Box 9)
      - A Memoir of Soho's Hayday (Box 9)
      - Mentmore Mania (Box 9)
      - Mentmore Bonanza (Box 16)
      - A Million Words (Box 9)
      - Nicking a Motor (Box 9)
      - Nine Lives in Soho (Box 9)
      - Nine Lives in Soho Synopsis (Box 16)
      - "Personal Opinion" (Box 9)
      - Picadilly Circus Article (Box 16)
      - Punch Up (Box 16)
      - Raymond Chandler (Box 9)
      - Roll Up! Roll Up! (Box 9)
      - The Prison Officer's Dispute (Box 9)
      - Screwing a Gaff (Box 16)
      - Sir Noel Coward (Box 16)
      - Soho (Box 9)
      - Soho Kaleidoscope (Box 16)
      - Spectator Bash (Box 9)
      - Taxi (Box 16)
      - Tom Keating Article (Box 9)
      - Working Holiday (Box 16)
      - Working with Joan Littlewood (Box 9)
      - Working with Joan Littlewood Proposal (Box 16)
      - Wry Eye (Box 16)
      - Unidentified Article Fragments (Box 9)
    - Magazines (Box 10)
      - Sex in High Society (Box 10)
      - Up the Manor (Box 10)
      - Farewell to Hampstead (Box 10)
      - Playwright's Progress (Box 10)
      - New York! New York! (Box 10)
      - Perfumes Gentlemen Prefer, 1960 (Box 10)
      - Burglar to the Nobility Review, 1961 (Box 10)
      - Danmarks Soho, 1962 (Box 10)
      - Victims of the Law, 1969 (Box 10)
      - Would the Real Frank Harris, 1975 (Box 10)
      - Wish You Were Here?, 1975 (Box 10)
      - Colin MacInnes, 1976 (Box 10)
      - American Cameos, 1975 (Box 10)
      - The Most Famous Pub in Soho, 1976 (Box 10)
      - Lying Low with Tom Keating, 1976 (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956-1982 (Box 10)
      - Encounter December 1956 (Box 10)
      - Encounter March 1957 (Box 10)
      - Encounter July 1957 (Box 10)
      - Encounter October 1957 (Box 10)
      - Encounter June 1958 (Box 10)
      - Encounter October 1958 (Box 10)
      - Encounter February 1959 (Box 10)
      - Encounter March 1959 (Box 10)
      - Encounter December 1962 (Box 10)
      - Encounter February 1963 (Box 10)
      - Encounter June 1971 (Box 10)
      - The Tatler, 1962 (Box 10)
      - Sparrows Can't Sing Program, 1963 (Box 10)
      - Evergreen September 1965 (Box 10)
      - Evergreen June 1968 (Box 10)
      - Club International, 1972 (Box 10)
      - Books and Bookmen June 1975 (Box 10)
      - Punch, 1977 (Box 10)
      - Private Eye November 1979 (Box 10)
      - Spectator January 1982 (Box 10)
      - Sunday Times Article Proofs (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
    - "Pages of Daring Style Notes" (Box 16)
    - Fame Synopsis (Box 16)
    - "First Poem" (Box 16)
    - Tales of Picadilly Synopsis (Box 16)
    - Barnardo (Box 16)
    - Anguillara Sabazia (Box 16)
    - The Do-Gooders Synopsis (Box 16)
    - Father of the Child Bride (Box 16)
    - "Random Notes" (Box 16)
    - About the Screwman's Lament (Box 16)
    - "F.N. Bio Note" (Box 16)
    - Mixed Drafts with Notes (Box 16)
    - Misc Notes 1964-1977 (Box 17)
- Press (Box 10)
  - Stand on Me, 1961 (Box 10)
    - Newsweek, 1961 (Box 10)
  - A Kayf Up West, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Preview Invitation, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Sunday Times Article Proof (Ovflat Unknown)
  - Soho Night and Day, 1968 (Box 10)
    - Queen, 1968 (Box 10)
  - Insideout, 1969-1970 (Box 10)
    - Publicity Schedule, 1969 (Box 10)
    - Royal Court Press Release, 1969 (Box 10)
    - Plays and Players, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Insideout Posters (Ovflat Unknown)
    - Article Proof (Ovflat 37)
    - Notes - Memorandum Book (Box 16)
  - Dodgem Greaser, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Hodder and Stoughton New Books, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Costa Packet, 1972 (Box 10)
    - Postcards, 1972 (Box 10)
    - Costa Packet Posters (Ovflat Unknown)
  - Why Fings Went West, 1975 (Box 10)
    - First Harvest, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Banana Boy, 1975 (Box 10)
    - Speak BBC Radio, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Too Many Crooks Spoil the Caper, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Spectator, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Fings Ain't Wot They Used T'Be, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Hexagon Flyer, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Lincoln Theatre Royal Flyer A (Box 10)
    - Lincoln Theatre Royal Flyer B (Ovflat Unknown)
  - In the Nick (Box 10)
    - In the Nick Poster (Ovflat 37)
  - Programs 1958-1972 1/2 (Box 10)
  - Programs 1958-1972 2/2 (Box 10)
  - International Film and Television Yearbook no date (Box 10)
  - Articles About Frank, 1960-1981 (Box 10)
    - Plays and Players 1960 (Box 10)
    - New Departures, 1981 (Box 10)
    - Spectator, 1981 (Box 10)
    - Conteporary Authors (Box 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1958-1980 (Box 10)
    - Loose Scrapbook Pages 1972-1978 (Box 10)
    - Clippings 1980
    - "Newspaper Cuttings" Green Binding A, 1958 (Box 11)
    - Blue and Black Binding, 1958-1960 (Box 11)
    - "Newspaper Cuttings" Red Binding, 1960 (Box 11)
    - "Newspaper Cuttings" Green Binding B, 1968-1969 (Box 11)
    - "Cuttings Book", 1969-1972 (Box 11)
    - Navy Blue Scrapbook, 1977-1980 (Box 11)
  - Collected Press, 1950-1980 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1950s, 1950-1959 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1959-1961 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1962 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1963-1969, 1964-1969 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1969 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1970 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1971 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1972 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1973 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1974 1/2 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1974 2/2 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1975 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1976 (Box 12)
    - Collecetd Press 1977 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1978 1/3 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1978 2/3 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press 1978 3/3 (Box 12)
    - Collected Press from Gillon Aitken (Box 12)
- Correspondence, 1950-1981 (Box 12)
  - Professional, 1950-1981 (Box 12)
    - 1950s, 1950-1959 (Box 12)
    - 1960s 1/6, 1960-1969 (Box 12)
    - 1960s 2/6, 1960-1969 (Box 12)
    - 1960s 3/6, 1960-1969 (Box 12)
    - 1960s 4/6, 1960-1969 (Box 13)
    - 1960s 5/6, 1960-1969 (Box 13)
    - 1960s 6/6, 1960-1969 (Box 13)
    - 1970s 1/13, 1970-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1970s 2/13, 1970-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1970s 3/13, 1970-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1970s 4/13, 1970-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1970s 5/13, 1970-1979
    - 1970s 6/13, 1970-1979
    - 1970s 7/13, 1970-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1970s 8/13, 1970-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1970s 9/13, 1970-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1970s 10/13, 1970-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1970s 11/13, 1970-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1970s 12/13, 1970-1979 (Box 14)
    - 1970s 13/13, 1970-1979 (Box 14)
    - 1980s, 1980-1981 (Box 14)
    - 1964-1969 (Box 16)
    - 1970 (Box 16)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 16)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 17)
    - Spectator Article Rejection (Box 16)
    - New Statesman Article Rejection (Box 16)
    - Sunday Times "Love Story" Article Rejection (Box 16)
    - Correspondence 1973-1977 (Box 16)
    - Punch "Love Story" Article Rejection (Box 16)
    - The Job Production Rejection, 1970 (Box 16)
    - Working Holiday Article Rejection, 1970 (Box 16)
    - Tony Parker Letter Draft (Box 16)
  - Personal, 1960-1980 (Box 14)
    - "Letters to Family and Friends and Occasional Foe" 1/2, 1960-1980 (Box 14)
    - "Letters to Family and Friends and Occasional Foe" 2/2, 1960-1980 (Box 14)
    - Fan Mail, 1960-1980 (Box 14)
    - Letter to Unknown Recipient (Box 14)
    - 1969-1971 (Box 17)